export const SOCIALSTUDIESA2012 = [

{
id: "question1",
question: "1. A constitution is important for a county because it",
A: "allows the government to exercise absolute power",
B: "serves as the basis for good government",
C: "defends the county against external aggression",
D: "makes the county self-reliant",
answer: "B. serves as the basis for good government",
correctLetter: "B",
correctOption: 2,
},

{
id: "question2",
question: "2. The imposition of curfew limits mainly the individual’s freedom of",
A: "movement",
B: "worship",
C: "ownership",
D: "association",
answer: "A. movement",
correctLetter: "A",
correctOption: 1,
},

{
id: "question3",
question: "3. A characteristic of a buoyant economy is high",
A: "mortality rate",
B: "standard of living",
C: "birth rate",
D: "level of illiteracy",
answer: "B. standard of living",
correctLetter: "B",
correctOption: 2,
},

{
id: "question4",
question: "4. The body responsible for protecting people’s rights against all forms of abuse is the",
A: "Children’s Right International",
B: "Commission on Human Rights and Administrative Justice",
C: "National Media Commission",
D: "National Commission for Civic Education",
answer: "B. Commission on Human Rights and Administrative justice",
correctLetter: "B",
correctOption: 2,
},

{
id: "question5",
question: "5. A leadership style which is highly coercive and intolerant of opposing views is",
A: "autocratic",
B: "democratic",
C: "laissez-faire",
D: "paternalistic",
answer: "A. autocratic",
correctLetter: "A",
correctOption: 1,
},

{
id: "question6",
question: "6. The doctrine that no two government powers are entrusted into the same hands is known as",
A: "the rule of law",
B: "checks and balances",
C: "separation of power",
D: "democratic rule",
answer: "C. separation of power",
correctLetter: "C",
correctOption: 3,
},

{
id: "question7",
question: "7. In a democratic governance, power is balanced to ensure that",
A: "individuals’ rights are not trampled upon",
B: "wealth is distributed equally",
C: "the electoral system can satisfy the ruling party",
D: "majority interest can be catered for",
answer: "A. individuals rights are not trampled upon",
correctLetter: "A",
correctOption: 1,
},

{
id: "question8",
question: "8. Irresponsible parenting is on the increase in developing counties due to",
A: "abject poverty",
B: "illiteracy",
C: "widowhood",
D: "immigration",
answer: "A. abject poverty",
correctLetter: "A",
correctOption: 1,
},

{
id: "question9",
question: "9. In the Ghanaian society, the fundamental aim of naming a child is to",
A: "present the baby with gifts",
B: "introduce the baby to water for the first time",
C: "make ancestors continue to have links with the baby",
D: "recognize the baby as a full member of the society",
answer: "D. recognize the baby as a full member of the society",
correctLetter: "D",
correctOption: 4,
},

{
id: "question10",
question: "10. One consequence of breakdown of marriages in the Ghanaian society is",
A: "brain drain",
B: "high infant mortality rate",
C: "excessive quest for wealth",
D: "increase in streetism",
answer: "D. increase in streetism",
correctLetter: "D",
correctOption: 4,
},

{
id: "question11",
question: "11. In Ghana, marriage can be classified by the",
A: "residence of the couple",
B: "family background of the couple",
C: "process of courtship",
D: "size of audience at the marriage",
answer: "A. residence of the couple",
correctLetter: "A",
correctOption: 1,
},

{
id: "question12",
question: "12. Which of the following influences one’s personality?",
A: "Capability",
B: "Environment",
C: "Self-identity",
D: "Traits",
answer: "B. Environment",
correctLetter: "B",
correctOption: 2,
},

{
id: "question13",
question: "13. Knowledge of oneself helps the individual to",
A: "get the best employment",
B: "win national award",
C: "relate and interact with other people",
D: "appreciate other people’s views",
answer: "C. relate and interact with other people",
correctLetter: "C",
correctOption: 3,
},

{
id: "question14",
question: "14. Organized relationships and interactions among a group of people constitute their",
A: "culture",
B: "behavioural pattern",
C: "religion",
D: "social environment",
answer: "D. social environment",
correctLetter: "D",
correctOption: 4,
},

{
id: "question15",
question: "15. Which of the following is the main cause of environmental degradation in Ghana?",
A: "Scientific activities",
B: "Natural phenomenon",
C: "Biological activities",
D: "Human activities",
answer: "D. Human activities",
correctLetter: "D",
correctOption: 4,
},

{
id: "question16",
question: "16. Mechanisms of social control are meant to",
A: "ensure conformity to law and customs",
B: "encourage responsible parenting",
C: "discourage rural-urban migration",
D: "discourage adolescent chastity",
answer: "A. ensure conformity to law and customs",
correctLetter: "A",
correctOption: 1,
},

{
id: "question17",
question: "17. The process in which an individual learns a new lifestyle and discards his family’s values and customs is known as",
A: "culture-dynamics",
B: "reciprocal socialization",
C: "re-socialization",
D: "societal diffusion",
answer: "C. re-socialization",
correctLetter: "C",
correctOption: 3,
},

{
id: "question18",
question: "18. The most important agent of socialization in the Ghanaian traditional society is the",
A: "church",
B: "school",
C: "parents",
D: "mass media",
answer: "C. parents",
correctLetter: "C",
correctOption: 3,
},

{
id: "question19",
question: "19. Values that govern the behaviour of people in a particular society are known as",
A: "beliefs",
B: "norms",
C: "rites",
D: "traditions",
answer: "B. norms",
correctLetter: "B",
correctOption: 2,
},

{
id: "question20",
question: "20. Which of the following socio-cultural practices infringes on the rights o the individual in the Ghanaian society?",
A: "Chieftaincy",
B: "Festivals",
C: "Funeral rites",
D: "Trokosi system",
answer: "D. Trokosi system",
correctLetter: "D",
correctOption: 4,
},

{
id: "question21",
question: "21. One of the reasons for having many children in traditional Ghanaian society is that, they",
A: "link parents to ancestors",
B: "bring about celebration of naming ceremonies",
C: "are used for community work",
D: "bestow honour on the parents",
answer: "D. bestow honour on the parents",
correctLetter: "D",
correctOption: 4,
},

{
id: "question22",
question: "22. Female genital mutilation must be condemned in Ghana mainly because it",
A: "creates difficulty getting a partner",
B: "is associated with a particular ethnic group",
C: "goes against fundamental human rights",
D: "confines the individual to a particular location",
answer: "C. goes against fundamental human rights",
correctLetter: "C",
correctOption: 3,
},

{
id: "question23",
question: "23. The gradual reduction in the quality of the physical environment as a result of human and natural activities is referred to as",
A: "decongestion",
B: "deforestation",
C: "degradation",
D: "desertification",
answer: "C. degradation",
correctLetter: "C",
correctOption: 3,
},

{
id: "question24",
question: "24. A family which cares for an abandoned child is known as",
A: "an extended family",
B: "a nuclear family",
C: "a family of procreation",
D: "an adoptive family",
answer: "D. an adoptive family",
correctLetter: "D",
correctOption: 4,
},

{
id: "question25",
question: "25. Family life education is important for the adolescent because it",
A: "promotes culture of reading",
B: "makes them socially knit",
C: "promotes responsible parenthood",
D: "enhances their understanding of national issues",
answer: "C. promotes responsible parenthood",
correctLetter: "C",
correctOption: 3,
},

{
id: "question26",
question: "26. Peer groups socialize their members through",
A: "direct teaching",
B: "informal teaching",
C: "non-formal teaching",
D: "systematic teaching",
answer: "D. systematic teaching",
correctLetter: "D",
correctOption: 4,
},

{
id: "question27",
question: "27. Which of the following practices is environmentally friendly?",
A: "Burning of fossil fuel",
B: "Creation of fetish groves",
C: "Periodic bush burning",
D: "Use of chemical for fishing",
answer: "B. Creation of fetish groves",
correctLetter: "B",
correctOption: 2,
},

{
id: "question28",
question: "28. Which of the following factors is not associated with population growth In Ghana?",
A: "Economic growth",
B: "Increase in crime wave",
C: "Pressure on land",
D: "Pressure on social amenities",
answer: "A. Economic growth",
correctLetter: "A",
correctOption: 1,
},

{
id: "question29",
question: "29. One effect of rural-urban migration on rural communities in Ghana is",
A: "growth of rural industries",
B: "collapse of rural industries",
C: "improvement in standard of living",
D: "rapid growth of rural population",
answer: "B. collapse of rural industries",
correctLetter: "B",
correctOption: 2,
},

{
id: "question30",
question: "30. Which of the following conditions can cause a change in the size of Ghana’s population?",
A: "Birth rate",
B: "Geographical mobility",
C: "Occupational mobility",
D: "Rural-urban migration",
answer: "A. Birth rate",
correctLetter: "A",
correctOption: 1,
},

{
id: "question31",
question: "31. Governments conduct population census mainly to",
A: "determine the international organization to join",
B: "determine the per capita income",
C: "plan the allocation of resources",
D: "divide the country into constituencies",
answer: "C. plan the allocation of resources",
correctLetter: "C",
correctOption: 3,
},

{
id: "question32",
question: "32. Which of the following cultural elements can bind Ghanaians together?",
A: "Architecture",
B: "Music and dance",
C: "Mode of dressing",
D: "Marriage",
answer: "D. Marriage",
correctLetter: "D",
correctOption: 4,
},

{
id: "question33",
question: "33. The bringing together of all individuals and their cultural units in the country is termed",
A: "nationalism",
B: "social allegiance",
C: "national integration",
D: "social co-operation",
answer: "C. national integration",
correctLetter: "C",
correctOption: 3,
},

{
id: "question34",
question: "34. Low productivity of Ghanaian workers is attributed to",
A: "lack of storage facilities",
B: "lack of supervision",
C: "decrease in population",
D: "decrease in the volume of exports",
answer: "B. lack of supervision",
correctLetter: "B",
correctOption: 2,
},

{
id: "question35",
question: "35. A benefit Ghana can derive from her membership of the African Union is",
A: "the development of nuclear capabilities",
B: "the sustenance of free movement with colonial allies",
C: "the enjoyment of friendship with other nations",
D: "longer tenure for political rulers",
answer: "C. the enjoyment of friendship with other nations",
correctLetter: "C",
correctOption: 3,
},

{
id: "question36",
question: "36. Which of the following is not a requirement for progress and development of the community?",
A: "Individuals having dual citizenship",
B: "People caring for one another",
C: "Individuals performing their roles",
D: "People performing communal labour",
answer: "A. Individuals having dual citizenship",
correctLetter: "A",
correctOption: 1,
},

{
id: "question37",
question: "37. The association comprising mainly of Britain and her former colonies is the",
A: "league of nations",
B: "Commonwealth of Nations",
C: "North Atlantic Treaty Organisation",
D: "Non-Aligned Movement",
answer: "B. Commonwealth of Nations",
correctLetter: "B",
correctOption: 2,
},

{
id: "question38",
question: "38. In which of the following ways has science and technology negatively affected mankind?",
A: "Invention of weapons of war",
B: "The use of hook and line in fishing",
C: "Reduction in the use of traditional farming implement",
D: "The use of storage facilities",
answer: "A. Invention of weapons of war",
correctLetter: "A",
correctOption: 1,
},

{
id: "question39",
question: "39. All the following can help improve the standard of living in Ghana except",
A: "changing negative attitudes",
B: "good banking and savings habits",
C: "making education accessible to all",
D: "depending on family members",
answer: "D. depending on family members",
correctLetter: "D",
correctOption: 4,
},

{
id: "question40",
question: "40. One factor hindering economic development in Ghana is",
A: "shortage of labour",
B: "shortage of food",
C: "poor entrepreneurial abilities",
D: "poor climatical conditions",
answer: "C. poor entrepreneurial abilities",
correctLetter: "C",
correctOption: 3,
},

{
id: "question41",
question: "41. One effect of negative work attitudes in Ghana is",
A: "lack of job satisfaction",
B: "reduction in labour turnover",
C: "reduction in production cost",
D: "reduction of profit",
answer: "D. reduction of profit",
correctLetter: "D",
correctOption: 4,
},

{
id: "question42",
question: "42. The best way of dealing with conflicts in the workplaces is through",
A: "violent demonstration",
B: "dialogue",
C: "the use of arms",
D: "strikes",
answer: "B. dialogue",
correctLetter: "B",
correctOption: 2,
},

{
id: "question43",
question: "43. In Ghana, the sole proprietor can source for finance in all the following ways except",
A: "sale of shares",
B: "trade credit",
C: "loans from commercial banks",
D: "ploughing back profits",
answer: "A. sale of shares",
correctLetter: "A",
correctOption: 1,
},

{
id: "question44",
question: "44. One purpose of setting up public corporations in Ghana is to",
A: "create employment for party members",
B: "meet the requirements of donor agencies",
C: "provide essential services to the public",
D: "generate income for government officials",
answer: "C. provide essential services to the public",
correctLetter: "C",
correctOption: 3,
},

{
id: "question45",
question: "45. The term physical environment refers to the",
A: "living organisms and their surroundings",
B: "political and economic surroundings",
C: "cultural and social surroundings of human beings",
D: "interaction of living organisms",
answer: "A. living organism and their surroundings",
correctLetter: "A",
correctOption: 1,
},

{
id: "question46",
question: "46. Which of the following elements is not a characteristic of culture? It is",
A: "dynamic",
B: "inherited",
C: "learned",
D: "universal",
answer: "B. inherited",
correctLetter: "B",
correctOption: 2,
},

{
id: "question47",
question: "47. In most Ghanaian societies, widowhood rites entail",
A: "fasting and prayers",
B: "seclusion of the widow",
C: "wearing of the deceased’s clothes",
D: "the widow inheriting the deceased",
answer: "B. seclusion of the widow",
correctLetter: "B",
correctOption: 2,
},

{
id: "question48",
question: "48. The type of marriage in which the couple continues to live separately in their own homes after marriage is",
A: "duolocal",
B: "matrilocal",
C: "neolocal",
D: "patrilocal",
answer: "A. duolocal",
correctLetter: "A",
correctOption: 1,
},

{
id: "question49",
question: "49. Which of the following is not a means by which the private entrepreneur can sustain his/her business?",
A: "having a huge amount of capital",
B: "applying a huge amount of capital",
C: "maintaining a high quality product",
D: "separating personal accounts from business account",
answer: "A. having a huge amount of capital",
correctLetter: "A",
correctOption: 1,
},

{
id: "question50",
question: "50. A merit of sole proprietorship is",
A: "enjoyment of flexibility in operation",
B: "enjoyment of limited liability",
C: "raising funds on the stock market",
D: "separation of management and control",
answer: "A. enjoyment of flexibility in operation",
correctLetter: "A",
correctOption: 1,
},


]